Ah, I see. I can't enter Kamihama because Alina Gray has the whole city covered by a magical barrier.
Oh well. I have a good idea of what's going on in there.
You magical girls must have figured out how to use the doppel effect that occurs in the barrier to keep yourselves from turning into witches.
You're right about one thing. You're not obligated to become witches.
But not only are you wasting your precious souls trying to escape your fate as magical girls, you have no problem if your actions harm all of humankind in the process.
Honestly, I don't understand you.
You've created a truly magnificent piece of art!
I was getting so bored playing with these goody-goody girls and their niente souls.
Your next piece will be even more high-class and filled with emotiva.
At least that's what I'm hoping for.
Where is Walpurgis knocked now?
Still on course. She's heading straight for Mitakihara at the same speed.
You think we can catch up to her?
It'll be close, but we'll make it in time.
Then let's go.
For the future of Magical Girls!
And for our big sis, Iroha.
Your insane plan!
Is the last thing she'd want!
Stop this! You have no idea what you're doing!
We calculated all the risks, actually.
For example, right now, we're at less than 1% of our total estimated casualties.
You are insane!
Two huge witches fusing has the same effect as two black holes fusing.
We estimate that when Embryo Eve absorbs Walpurgis knocked, it will create a massive shockwave of energy.
But with our new system in place, Magical Girls won't ever become witches again.
Yachiyo, what's going on? What is that?
If we can change things, it's our duty to change them.
You're seeing Ui's wish, Toka's wish, and mine.
This is our three wishes fulfilled.
As for Iroha, we put her someplace safe till this is over.
So don't you worry!
You should find somewhere safe to hide, too.
Originally, the universe was fated to end in the future, from heat death.
Luckily, my kind found a way to extend its lifespan.
During puberty, when the hope a young human girl possesses shifts into despair, it creates a massive amount of energy.
It's miraculous emotional energy, strong enough to hold back the tides of entropy.
All of you are incredibly valuable.
You're the key to extending the lifespan of the universe, after all.
And if you really think about the conditions of the contracts you made with me, why, they're in your favor.
That's how a Magical Girl's contract works.
I don't agree with what the Magiists claim, that the fate of a Magical Girl is tragic.
Becoming a witch isn't just the price you have to pay for the miracle you asked for.
It's your contribution to the survival of your species and the universe.
Think about it.
The future of the human race and the universe, or the end of it all.
Which would you choose?
I think it's obvious, don't you?
You, who've become Magical Girls.
It's my room.
How did I get back here?
I remember getting sealed in the teeny Q-bay by Nemu.
What's going on?
That's...
Yup.
Ui!
Oh, Ui, it's you!
It's you!
I missed you so much!
I missed you too, sis.
I looked for you.
I looked all over for you.
I know you did.
I know you tried.
I swear, I'll never let you go again.
You won't be alone anymore.
I'm sorry, sis.
Thanks, but I'm fine.
Huh?
Ui...
The day I became a Magical Girl, everything changed.
I changed.
I'm not me anymore.
Of course you are.
You're Ui.
The real Ui.
And I'm your big sis.
I am sorry, sis.
But we messed up.
We felt at everything we wanted.
We should have just left things alone, and...
In the end, we couldn't save anyone.
I'm sorry.
I don't care about that!
All I want is for you to be well again and happy.
That's it!
That's the only reason I became a Magical Girl!
It's what kept me going!
I know, but...
That's not fair, sis.
What about you?
I want you to be happy too, you know?
I wanted to save you from the fate of Magical Girls.
I wanted so much for you to be happy.
Why did everything have to happen the way it did?
It's okay, Ui.
I don't know how, but I'll figure out a way to fix all of it.
Please stop us, sis.
Do it for the sake of everyone.
Stop Embryo Eve.
And Nemu and Touka, too.
I care about you so much, and I want to save you from a Magical Girl's horrible fate.
But if our plan succeeds, you're going to regret not stopping us when you have the chance.
So please...
But Ui, if I can stop you guys, will that turn you back to normal?
Tell me you'll turn back!
Please!
Hang on.
I'll find a way to get you out of here.
Why do you look like that?
Come with me, Ui!
It's too late for me.
But there's others who need your help.
So be strong.
Because there's a bunch of people whose hands you're going to have to hold.
Stop it!
Please, let me see you again!
There's no time now.
Your friend needs you.
She's the first of many people you'll have to save when you get back.
So go.
Help her.
Ui!
I'm sorry I caused so much trouble for you.
Thank you for being the best, sis.
I love you.
Ui!
Why are you here, Iroha?
Curly!
You shouldn't have come.
It's not like there's anything you can do to help.
Your doppel's taking over!
Stop using it!
I don't care anymore.
Curly!
Don't let your doppel get the tr-
Why fight it?
I gave up on everything.
A long time ago.
Curly!
On that day, I abandoned everything I was.
Just like I abandoned her.
I gave up.
The fate of a magical girl.
The fate of a magical girl was a heavier burden than I expected.
Which is a really strong, and beating them's hard.
But the only way you can get grief seeds is by beating them.
Even though I had all these powers as a magical girl, I couldn't get that strong.
I didn't know how long I'd survive like that.
But there was a girl who was even weaker than me.
Way, way weaker.
Are you okay?
Oh my gosh!
Watch out!
I thought I was gonna die in there. Thanks for saving me.
Sure.
I don't know you. Are you new?
Yes. I don't live around here though.
Oh. Well, since you're new and not from here, you're kinda on my turf.
You're supposed to fight the witches in your own area, not the ones in someone else's.
It's one of the rules of this job.
I'm so sorry. I saw the kitty run into the labyrinth and I followed it. I swear, it'll never happen again.
Don't worry about it. This stuff happens sometimes.
Y-you're not mad?
Uh-uh. Bye.
What?
I hate to ask this, but do you have an extra grief seed?
See, my soul gen got pretty tainted after that fight. So, if you had one...
Sorry.
Oh, don't apologize. I mean, who's got extra grief seeds, right? I shouldn't have even asked. It was dumb.
No, it's not. But I don't have any. I'm not strong enough to get any myself.
I'm sorry.
No, you don't have to apologize. I shouldn't have even asked you. I'm sorry.
Still, I feel bad.
Not even. I was dumb. I should have brought along some extras.
Anyway, thanks again for saving me. I mean it. I hate to think what would have happened to me and the kitty without you.
Sure.
I-I'm still new at this, but I promise. I'll work hard and be a great magical girl someday.
I'll get enough grief seeds for everyone that no one's gonna run out.
Yeah. Let's do our best.
Yeah! Right. Let's do our best.
We never asked each other's names. We didn't even share our contact info, so we could stay in touch.
That was the last time I saw her at that station.
She kept waving at me and didn't stop.
She just kept waving and waving.
She was scared, too.
What would you have done, Iroha?
I wonder what happened to her.
Did she go and join the Magius?
Is she even still alive?
On that day, I gave up.
Instead of helping her, I abandoned her.
I'm not like you, Iroha.
Not even close.
Please, go away!
My dad! You have this job!
I could have helped her, but I didn't.
I chose not to.
Hang on a little longer!
I'm here! I'll save you!
The idea of what a magical girl should be is a reflection of the ethical values of humans and changes depending on the era.
Magical girls have always been considered holy due to their special powers.
The masses want someone to look up to, and magical girls personify that ideal.
Throughout your history, my kind has done everything possible to accommodate those desires.
But going back to what I was saying about changing values,
in some eras, justice meant saving the weak.
In other eras, it meant eliminating the weak to strengthen society and save it from extinction.
You see, the concept of justice, or what you humans believe is right,
changed depending on the era in which you lived.
Therefore, your attempt at keeping magical girls from their fate,
this temporary salvation you're offering them,
is nothing but a reflection of this era's wave of thinking.
Instead of the Magius' plan, which is based on temporary ideology,
our system, which offers your species' perpetual growth and prosperity,
is much better for you humans.
I can't understand why this is so difficult for you to accept.
I'll be honest, Cube, your fuzzy kind's visione missione stir nothing in my cuore.
But the fate you so kindly shared tells me one thing,
that our culture and civilization were created by feeding them the souls
of all the magical girls you tricked.
Destroying your kind, Eon Duvere?
That goes without saying.
But do you know who I think really deserves restituire
for all the years of unfairness and exploitation?
Well, it should be obvious.
Or isn't it?
I wasn't strong enough to be part of the Magius.
Or strong enough to be like you.
Shut up!
I couldn't be anything.
I'm nobody.
I'm nothing.
Stop that!
I don't care what you say!
I'm going to save you!
Yeroha?
Kuroi!
Kana!
Yeroha...
With a combined attack,
we might be able to break you out of it.
But I can't move my body.
Try harder!
I did.
I can't.
I'll save you, you hear me?
I'll save everyone!
No way am I going to let Ui down!
There's no point saving me.
I'm useless.
I'm weak.
But together, we can be strong.
If it's too hard to get stronger yourself,
we can get strong together!
I don't think I can.
No matter how hard things get,
as long as someone's there for you,
you can face anything!
I was scared and weak too,
but I had my friends to help me!
But I...
Kuroi!
Let's do our best!
Right!
You had the chance!
Why didn't you do the right thing
and save her?
You had the chance to do the right thing to do with you!
Come on!
What's wrong with me?
You've been so nice to me.
You've done so much for me.
So...
Why do I feel so pathetic?
I shouldn't have made that wish
or wanted to save anyone.
I should have stayed normal!
You can be strong just like me.
You're a magical girl.
Our strength comes from hopes and wishes, after all.
Don't give up on yourself or your wish.
Kuroi, when you made your wish,
who was it for?
I don't remember.
What was it?
Kuroi!
Become a magical girl like me!
Hey, Ira...
Tell me...
How long do I have to keep being a magical girl?
We just broke through Alina's barrier.
Oh no!
We're outside the doppel system now!
It's impossible for me to be...
the person I hope to be.
So I thought...
maybe...
if I became this,
I'd stop hating myself.
And I'd go back to before I met you.
No, no one will save me.
No, I don't need to save anyone.
No, I can stop being a magical boy.
Oh my God.
Now, are you watching those days over here?
I'm sorry, Yui. Your big sister let you down.